( typewriter clacking )
( typewriter dings )
( slow piano music )
Still got it
( " Shotgun " by Junior Walker The All Stars )
♫ I said , Shotgun
♫ Shoot ' em ' fore he runs now
♫ Do the jerk , baby
♫ Do the jerk now
♫ Hey
♫ Put on your red dress
♫ And then you go downtown now
♫ I said , buy yourself a shotgun now
♫ We 're gonna break it down baby now
♫ We 're gonna load it up baby now
♫ And then you shoot him ' fore he runs now
♫ I said , Shotgun
♫ Shoot ' em ' fore he runs now
♫ Do the jerk , baby
♫ Do the jerk now
♫ Hey
♫ Put on your high-heeled shoes
♫ I said , we 're goin ' down here listen to ' em play the blues
♫ We 're gonna dig potatoes
♫ We 're gonna pick tomatoes
♫ I said , Shotgun
♫ Shoot ' em ' fore he runs now
♫ Do the jerk , baby
♫ Do the jerk now
♫ Hey
♫ I said it 's Twine Time
( tire squealing )
( engine revving )
( metal crunching )
( wind blowing )
[ Woman ] What 's that ?
An old friend .
I was rummaging through a closet
and it was just sitting there .
It 's nice , Paul .
It 's got character .
When I wrote my first book ,
I used to carry it around in this
while I was looking for a publisher .
I was a writer then .
You 're still a writer .
Haven 't been a writer since I got in the Misery business .
It 's not a bad business .
And it would still be growing , too .
The first printing for Misery 's Child was the most ever .
Over a million .
[ Paul ] Marcia , please .
Misery Chastain put braces on your daughter 's teeth
and is putting her through college ,
bought you two houses and floor seats to the Knicks .
And what thanks does she get ?
You go and kill her .
I never meant for it to become my life .
And if I hadn 't gotten rid of her now ,
I 'd have ended up writing her forever .
Now , I 'm leaving for Colorado to try to finish the new book .
If I can make this work I might just have something
I want on my tombstone .
( wind blowing )
( metal creaking )
( gasping )
[ Woman ] I 'm your number one fan .
There 's nothing to worry about .
You 're gonna be just fine .
I 'll take good care of you .
I 'm your number one fan .
Where ?
We 're just outside Silver Creek .
How long ?
You 've been here two days .
You 're gonna be okay .
My name is Annie Wilkes .
My number one fan .
( laughs ) Yes , that 's right .
I 'm also a nurse .
Here , take these .
( subdued music )
Here .
What are they ?
They 're called Novril .
They 're for your pain .
Thank you .
How come I 'm not in a hospital ?
The blizzard was too strong .
I couldn 't risk trying to get you there .
I tried calling , but the phone lines are down .
( gasps )
Now , you mustn 't tire yourself .
You 've gotta rest .
You almost died .
Open wide .
Your legs just sing grand opera when you move , don 't they ?
It 's not gonna hurt forever , Paul .
I promise you .
Will I be able to walk ?
Of course , you will .
And your arm will be fine , too .
Your shoulder was pretty badly dislocated .
It was a little stubborn , but I finally popped it back in .
What I 'm most proud of is the work I did on those legs .
Considering what I had around the house ,
I don 't think there 's a doctor who could 've done any better .
( tense music )
It 's not nearly as bad as it looks .
You have a compound fracture of the tibia in both legs ,
and the fibula in the right leg is fractured , too .
I could hear the bones moving ,
so it 's best for your legs to remain immobile .
And as soon as the roads open , I 'll take you to a hospital .
Meantime , you 've got a lot of recovering to do ,
and I consider it an honor that you 'll do it in my home .
This is Marcia Sindell .
I 'm calling from New York City .
I 'd like to speak to the Silver Creek
chief of police or sheriff .
[ Man On Phone ] Which one of ' em do you want ?
Whichever one 's not busy .
Well , I 'm pretty sure they 're both not busy , Ms. Sindell ,
since they 're both me .
I also happen to be president of the
Policeman 's Benefit Association ,
chairman of the Patrolman 's Retirement Fund ,
and if you need a good fishing guide ,
you could do a lot worse .
Call me Buster .
Everybody does .
What can I do for you ?
I 'm a literary agent , and I feel like a fool calling you ,
but I think one of my clients , Paul Sheldon ,
might be in some kind of trouble .
You mean Paul Sheldon the writer ?
[ Marcia On Phone ] Uh-huh .
He 's your client , huh ?
[ Marcia On Phone ] Yes , he is .
Everybody sure likes those Misery books .
Yeah .
I 'm sure you know that Paul 's been coming to
the Silver Creek Lodge for years to finish his books .
I understand he 's been up here the last six weeks .
Well , not quite .
I just called there and they said
he checked out last Tuesday .
Isn 't that a little strange ?
Oh , I don 't know .
Does he usually phone you before he checks out of a hotel ?
No .
No , of course not .
It 's just that his daughter hasn 't heard from him ,
and when he has a new book coming out ,
he usually keeps in touch .
Now , when there wasn 't any word from him , I ...
You think he might be missin ' , huh ?
( sighs ) I hate that I made this call .
Tell me I 'm being silly .
Oh , a little overprotective , maybe ,
but tell you what I 'll do .
Nothing 's been reported out here ,
but I 'll put his name through our system .
If anything turns up , I 'll call you right back .
[ Marcia On Phone ] I 'd appreciate that .
Thanks a lot .
Goodbye , Ms. Sindell .
We got a phone call ?
Busy morning .
Yeah .
Work , work , work .
Virginia , when was that blizzard ?
Last Tuesday .
Why ?
No reason .
I guess it was kind of a miracle , you finding me .
( laughs ) No , it wasn 't a miracle at all .
In a way , I was following you .
You were following me ?
Well , it wasn 't any secret to me
you were staying at the Silver Creek ,
seeing as how I 'm your number one fan and all .
Some nights I 'd just tool on down there ,
and sit outside , and look up at the light in your cabin ,
and I 'd try to imagine what was goin ' on in the room
of the world 's greatest writer .
Say the last part again , I didn 't hear you .
Don 't move now .
I wouldn 't want to hurt this neck .
Well , the other afternoon I was on my way home ,
and there you were , leavin ' the lodge .
And I wondered why a literary genius would go for a drive
when there was a big storm comin ' .
I didn 't know there was a big storm coming .
Well , lucky for you , I did .
And lucky for me , too ,
' cause now you 're alive and you can write more books .
Oh , Paul .
I 've read everything of yours .
But , the Misery novels .
I know ' em all by heart .
All eight of ' em .
I love them so .
Well , you 're very kind .
And you 're very brilliant .
Like a baby .
All done .
Thank you .
When do you think the phone lines will be up ?
I have to call my daughter ,
and I 'd like to call my agent in New York
and let her know I 'm still breathing .
It shouldn 't be too much longer now .
Once the roads are open ,
the phone lines will be up in no time .
If you give me their numbers , I 'll keep tryin ' them for you .
[ Paul ] Thank you .
Could I ask you a favor ?
I noticed in your case there 's a new Paul Sheldon book ,
and I wondered if maybe ...
You want to read it ?
Well , if you wouldn 't mind .
Well , I do have a very hard-and-fast rule
as to who reads my stuff at this early stage .
Only my editor , my agent , and anybody that saves me
from freezing to death in a car wreck .
Oh .
You 'll never realize what a rare treat you 've given me .
( groans )
Boy , it 's like clockwork the way your pain comes .
I 'll get you your Novril , Paul .
Forgive me for prattling away and making you feel all oogy .
What 's your new book called ?
I don 't have a title yet .
[ Annie ] What 's it about ?
I don 't know .
I know it sounds crazy , but I haven 't written anything
but Misery for so long .
Why don 't you read it and you can tell me
what you think it 's about ?
Maybe you can come up with a title .
Like I could do that .
There 's nothin ' unusual about
Mr. Sheldon 's leaving , Buster .
You can tell by the champagne .
Maybe you can , Libby .
No , see , he always orders a bottle of Dom Perignon
when he 's ready to go .
Then , he pays up and he 's out the door .
No long-distance phone calls or Federal Express packages ?
Anything out of the ordinary ?
I don 't think Mr. Sheldon
likes for things to be out of the ordinary .
Considering who he is and all , famous and all ,
he doesn 't put on airs .
Drives up from New York in the same car each time .
A ' 65 Mustang .
He says it helps him to think .
He 's always been a good guest .
Never makes a noise , never bothers a soul .
I sure hope nothing 's happened to him .
So do I.
I bet that old Mustang is pulling into New York right now .
I 'm sure you 're right .
Thanks , Libby .
[ Libby ] My pleasure .
I know I 'm only 40 pages into your book , but ...
But what ?
Nothing .
What is it ?
It 's ridiculous .
Who am I to make a criticism to someone like you ?
It 's all right , I can take it .
Well , it 's brilliantly written .
But then , everything you write is brilliant .
Pretty rough so far .
The swearing , Paul .
There , I said it .
The profanity bothers you ?
It has no nobility .
These are slum kids .
I was a slum kid .
Everybody talks like that .
They do not !
What do you think I say when I go to the feed store in town ?
Now , Wally , give me a bag of that F-ing pig feed
and 10 pounds of that bitchly cow corn .
And in the bank , do I tell Mrs. Bollinger ,
here 's one big bastard of a check ,
give me some of your Christing money ?
There !
Look there !
See what you made me do ?
Oh , Paul .
I 'm sorry .
I 'm so sorry .
Sometimes I get so worked up .
Can you ever forgive me ?
It 's fine .
I love you , Paul .
Your mind .
Your creativity .
That 's all I meant .
( upbeat music )
Well , this sure is fun .
Virginia , when you 're in this car you 're not my wife ,
you 're my deputy .
Well , this deputy 'd rather be home
under the covers with the sheriff .
Stop .
What ?
Stop !
( tires squeal )
See that broken limb ?
Could 've been the weight of the snow .
Yeah ?
Could 've been a rotten branch .
Could 've been the wind .
Could 've been a lot of things .
( grunts )
Damn !
Need some help ?
No , I 'm enjoyin ' myself !
Thank you .
( subdued music )
You really think Sheldon 's out there ?
I hope not .
If he is , he 's dead .
Let 's go to the newspaper office .
( doorknob rattling )
( door creaking )
Oh , I hope I didn 't wake you .
No , that 's fine .
Look what I got .
They had it at the store , Paul .
There was a whole batch of ' em there ,
and as soon as I saw it I slammed my money down .
I got the first copy .
Then , the roads are open .
Well , the one to town is , but that 's about it .
I called the hospital
and I talked to the head orthopedic surgeon
and I told him who you were and what had happened .
And he said as long as there 's no infection
you 're not in any danger .
And as soon as the road to the hospital is open ,
they 'll send an ambulance for you .
The phone 's working ?
Well , mine 's still out ,
but the ones in town were working just fine .
I called that agent of yours .
Oh , Paul .
I peeked at the very beginning .
What a wonderful first page .
Just to read the name Misery Chastain .
My daughter 's gotta be goin ' nuts .
It 's like a visit from my oldest , dearest friend .
I mean , I 'm supposed to be home for her birthday .
It 's today .
The agent said she would tell her you were okay ,
but I 'm afraid you 'll have to wait till tomorrow
if you want to talk to her yourself .
Oh , Paul .
What a poet you are .
I made you my specialty , scrambled eggs a la Wilkes .
And I 'm on Page 75 .
I guess that means it 's okay .
No .
No , it isn 't , it 's ...
Oh , pooh .
I can 't think of any words .
Would great be insulting ?
I can live with great .
No .
It 's not just great , it 's perfect .
A perfect , perfect thing .
( subdued music )
( door creaking )
( snorting )
I thought it was time you two should meet .
Paul , say hello to my favorite beast in the whole world ,
my sow Misery .
Misery ?
Yes .
I told you I was your number one fan .
Yeah , I 'm starting to believe you .
This farm was kind of dreary ,
what with just a few cows and chickens and me .
But , when I got Misery here , everything changed .
She just makes me smile so .
She 's a fine pig , is what she is .
I 'm on Page 300 now , Paul ,
and it 's better than perfect .
It 's divine .
What 's the ceiling that dago painted ?
The Sistine Chapel ?
Yeah !
That and Misery 's Child .
Those are the only two divine things ever in this world .
( snorting )
When my husband left me , I wasn 't prepared .
It wasn 't an easy time .
For a while I thought I might go crazy .
I know how that can be .
I don 't know about you ,
but what I did to get through it was I dove into work .
Days , nights .
Night shifts can be lonely at a hospital .
I did a lot of reading .
That was when I first discovered Misery .
She made me so happy .
She made me forget all my problems .
Course , I suppose you had a little something
to do with that , too .
Yeah , well .
I just kept reading them over and over .
I 've only got two chapters to go on this one
and I know when I finish I 'll just turn
right to the first page and start reading it all over again .
I 'm , uh .
Um .
Done ?
[ Paul ] Yeah .
No problem .
Thanks .
Don 't get me wrong .
I 'm not against marriage per se ,
but it 'd take a pretty special guy
to make me want to walk down that aisle again .
Yeah , it 's not something you should enter into lightly .
It boils down to respect .
People just don 't respect
the institution of marriage anymore .
They have no sense of real commitment .
Well , I 'd love to stay here and chat ,
but I 'm right at the end and I gotta find out what happens .
( door closes )
( door opens and closes )
You .
You dirty bird .
How could you ?
She can 't be dead .
Misery Chastain cannot be dead .
Annie , in 1871 , women often died in childbirth .
But , her spirit is the important thing ,
and Misery 's spirit is still alive .
I don 't want her spirit !
I want her !
And you murdered her !
No , I didn 't .
Who did ?
No one .
She died .
She just slipped away .
Slipped away ?
She didn 't just slip away !
You did it !
( pot shatters )
You murdered my Misery !
Annie , Annie !
( wood clatters )
I thought you were good , Paul .
But , you 're not good .
You 're just another lying old dirty birdie .
And I don 't think I better be around you for a while .
( tense music )
And don 't even think about anybody coming for you .
Not the doctors , not your agent , not your family ,
because I never called them .
Nobody knows you 're here .
And you better hope nothing happens to me .
Because if I die , you die .
( door closes )
( footsteps receding )
( car door opens and closes )
( car engine starts )
( breathing heavily )
( suspenseful music )
( grunting )
( yells )
( breathing heavily )
No , Ms. Sindell .
There 's no point in comin ' up here now .
Everything that can be done is .
Yes , we 're working close with the state police
and the FBI 's been informed .
Right .
As soon as we know anything , we 'll let you know .
No bother at all .
Call anytime .
Goodbye , Ms. Sindell .
All right .
Well , I sure appreciate it .
Thank you .
According to the check on Sheldon 's credit charges ,
there 's nothing after the Silver Creek .
And no calls about the article , either .
You poor , dear thing .
What are you doing on the floor ?
It 's all my fault .
If I 'd had a proper hospital bed
this never would 've happened .
Here , let me help you back in .
( grunts )
I know this hurts , but it 'll only take a few seconds .
Upsy-daisy .
( groaning )
Oh , please , wait , wait .
Oh , you 're such a crybaby .
Wait .
( grunting )
There you go .
Comfy ?
Perfect .
You 're such a kidder .
I have a big surprise for you .
But first , there 's something you must do .
You don 't suppose I could have a little snack
while I 'm waiting for the surprise ?
I 'll get you everything you want ,
but you must listen first .
Sometimes my thinking is a little muddy , I accept that .
That 's why I couldn 't remember all the things
they were asking me on the witness stand in Denver .
But , this time I thought clearly .
I asked God about you , and God said ,
" I delivered him unto you so that you may show him the way . "
Show me the way ?
Yes .
( wheels squeaking )
When I mentioned a snack ,
I was thinking more along the lines
of a cheese and crackers kind of thing .
Paul , this is no time for jokes .
You must rid the world of this filth .
You want me to burn my book ?
I know this may be difficult for you ,
but it 's for the best .
It 's really not difficult at all .
My agent made dozens of copies .
There 's gonna be an auction in New York .
Every publishing house in New York is reading it now .
So , if you want me to burn my book , fine .
You 're not really ridding the world of anything .
Then , light the match , Paul .
It 's no big deal .
So you 've indicated .
Do it .
I know this is the only copy , Paul .
When you were 24 you wrote your first book ,
and you didn 't make a copy because you didn 't think
anybody would take it seriously .
But , they did .
And ever since , you 've never made any copies
because you 're superstitious .
It 's why you always come back to the Silver Creek Lodge .
You told that story to Merv Griffin 11 years ago .
Merv Griffin .
I 'll tell you what .
It doesn 't ever have to be published .
No one ever has to read it .
I 'll just keep it for myself .
No one will even know it exists .
As long as it does exist , your mind won 't ever be free .
I think you should light the match , Paul .
Can 't you see it 's what God wants ?
You 're so brilliant ,
I would think you 'd certainly be able to see that .
We 're put on this earth to help people , Paul .
Like I 'm trying to help you .
Please .
Help me help you .
You 're doing the right thing .
Oh , my goodness !
Goodness gracious .
Oh , my .
Oh , goodness .
Heavens to Betsy .
Oh , my goodness .
Oh , goodness .
Well , isn 't that an oogy mess ?
( helicopter whirring )
That 's the Steadman place down there .
And that 's the Wilkes farm straight ahead .
That 's no ' 65 Mustang .
Well , there 's nothing else out this way .
Let 's circle back .
I do believe the winters are getting shorter
and shorter every year .
People say it has something to do with the ozone layer .
What do you think ?
I don 't know .
Yeah , well .
It 's a theory .
Here 's your Novril .
All right , we 're back .
Now , you 're gonna have to remind us who the audience chose .
They chose Kevin .
He 's backstage .
Say hello to Kevin Andrews .
Hi , Kevin .
Hi .
How you doin ' , Chuck ?
[ Chuck ] Fine .
Make yourself at home back there ,
and Sheree will tell us about the date .
Okay .
First of all , I picked out a very classy restaurant .
It was so classy , and he shows up without no tie .
No .
And he had these black shoes on .
[ Chuck ] What , did you tell him it was gonna be
kind of a formal evening ?
[ Sheree ] No .
Actually , I did not , but it doesn 't matter .
If someone knows they 're going out with Sharee Banks ,
they should be dressed very classy .
( TV audience cheers )
( people on TV chattering )
( fabric tearing )
[ Annie ] See , isn 't this nice ?
Great .
I always wanted to visit the other side of the room .
Ooh , and look what I got for you .
An electric razor , so you can shave yourself now .
( razor whirring )
If I knew this was gonna be the surprise ,
I 'd have burned all my books .
Now , don 't poke fun .
This is a very big day for you , Paul .
You just sit tight and I 'll set everything up .
Set what up ?
That 's the big surprise .
Your new studio .
After all , writers do need a place to work .
Work ?
You mean write ?
What in the world do you think I 'd write ?
Oh , but , Paul .
I don 't think , I know .
Now that you 've gotten rid of that nasty manuscript ,
you can go back to doing what you 're great at .
You 're gonna write a new novel ,
your greatest achievement ever .
Misery 's Return .
Misery 's Return ?
I know you didn 't mean it when you killed her ,
and now you 'll make it right .
It 'll be a book in my honor for saving your life
and nursing you back to health .
Oh , Paul .
You 're gonna make me the envy of the whole world .
You just expect me to whip something off , is that it ?
I expect nothing less than your masterpiece .
You do understand that this is not the ordinary way
in which books get written .
I mean , some people might actually
consider this an oddball situation .
I have total confidence in your brilliance .
Besides , the view will inspire you .
You just inhale that .
I 'll be right back .
I guess you don 't get bothered by neighbors much .
[ Annie ] Don 't you worry about that .
You 'll have total solitude
so you can concentrate on your work .
Great .
I got you this expensive paper to type on .
And I got a great deal on this 50-pound clunker ,
on account of its missing an N.
I told the saleslady N was one of the letters
in my favorite writer 's name .
It 's two of the letters in my favorite nurse 's name .
Annie .
You fooler .
Did I do good ?
You did great .
There is just one little thing .
I can 't work on this paper .
See , it 's Corrasable Bond and it smudges .
So , I thought maybe , if you went back into town ,
you could bring me some white long-grain mimeo .
But , mine cost the most ,
so I don 't see how it can smudge .
Come here , I 'll show you .
( typewriter clacking )
Oh , it does smudge , after all .
Isn 't that fascinating ?
[ Paul ] I thought you 'd be interested .
I 'd like for you to be in on everything , Annie .
Not just the finished book , but how it 's written .
Thank you for thinking of me .
Anything else I can get while I 'm in town ?
Any other crucial requirements that need satisfying ?
Would you like a tiny tape recorder ?
Or how about a handmade set of writing slippers ?
No , just the paper will be fine .
Are you sure ?
' Cause if you want , I 'll bring back the whole store for you .
Annie , what 's the matter ?
What 's the matter ?
I 'll tell you what 's the matter !
I go out of my way for you !
I do everything to try and make you happy !
I feed you , I clean you , I dress you ,
and what thanks do I get ?
Oh , you bought the wrong paper , Annie .
I can 't write on this paper , Annie !
Well , I 'll get your stupid paper ,
but you just better start showing me
a little more appreciation around here , Mr. Man !
( yells )
( door locks )
( car engine starts )
Shit .
Come on , you 've written about this , now do it .
( door unlocks )
What do you know ?
It actually works .
( groaning )
( tense music )
What a surprise .
You crazy bitch .
( groans )
( grunts )
( clock ticking )
( suspenseful music )
( grunting )
( breathing heavily )
( car approaching )
( dramatic music )
( grunts )
( door lock latches )
Paul , I 've got your paper .
I hope it 's enough .
It 's three reams of long-grain mimeo .
Just the kind you asked for .
Paul , you 're dripping with perspiration .
Your color is very hectic .
What have you been doing ?
You know damn well what I 've been doing .
I 've been sitting here suffering .
I need my pills .
Poor dear .
Let 's get you back in bed and I 'll get them for you .
I want my pills now .
It 'll only take a second .
No !
I want my pain to go away , Annie .
Please , make it go away .
Please , Annie .
Please .
It just breaks my heart to see you like this .
I 've done a lot of thinking on the drive .
Here you go .
And I 'm absolutely certain the main reason
I 've never been more popular is because of my temper .
You must be so mad at me .
The truth , now .
Well , who doesn 't let off a little steam
every once in a while ?
My genius needs his rest before he writes .
( Annie humming )
Footsies up .
There you go .
Okay .
( Annie humming )
Here .
In case you think of any ideas .
Well , I wouldn 't expect too much .
Don 't be silly .
You 'll be brilliant .
Think of me as your inspiration .
I have faith in you , my darling .
Catch this .
My darling .
( helicopter whirring )
The presumption must now be that Paul Sheldon is dead .
We know that he somehow managed
to crawl outside his vehicle ,
but we have been unable to find his body
anywhere in the vicinity of the accident .
We also know that if anyone had found him
they would have taken him to an area hospital .
Undoubtedly , he is buried somewhere out there in the snow .
We 'll find him after the first thaw .
That is , unless the animals didn 't get to him first ,
which is a distinct possibility .
That was a statement from
Colorado Police Chief Sherman Douglas .
We will be updating you with the latest .
( reporters chattering )
You don 't think he 's dead , do you ?
Well , he might well be , but not the way they say .
He never crawled out of that car by himself .
You can see the dents on the door there .
Someone pulled him out .
( chattering on TV )
( sniffing )
( typewriter clacking )
I 'm sorry , Paul .
This is all wrong .
What ?
You 'll have to do it over again .
It 's not worthy of you .
Throw it all out .
Except for that part of naming the gravedigger after me .
You can leave that in .
I really value your criticism ,
but maybe we 're being a little hasty here .
Paul , what you 've written just isn 't fair .
Not fair ?
That 's right .
When I was growing up in Bakersfield ,
my favorite thing in all the world
was to go to the movies on Saturday afternoons
for the chapter plays .
Cliffhangers .
I know that , Mr. Man !
They also call them serials !
I 'm not stupid , you know !
Anyway , my favorite was Rocketman ,
and once it was a no-brakes chapter ,
and the bad guys stuck him in a car on a mountain road ,
and knocked him out and welded the doors shut
and tore out the brakes and started him to his death .
And he woke up and tried to steer and tried to get out ,
but the car went off a cliff before he could escape ,
and it crashed and burned and I was so upset and excited .
And the next week , you better believe I was first in line .
And they always start with the end of the last week ,
and there was Rocketman , trying to get out ,
and here comes the cliff , and just before the car
went off the cliff he jumped free , and all the kids cheered .
But , I didn 't cheer .
I stood right up and started shouting ,
this isn 't what happened last week !
Have you all got amnesia ?
They just cheated us !
This isn 't fair !
He didn 't get out of the cockadoodie car !
They always cheated like that in chapter plays .
But , not you .
Not with my Misery .
Remember , Ian did ride for Dr. Cleary
at the end of the last book ,
but his horse fell jumping that fence ,
and Ian broke his shoulder and his ribs
and lay all night in the ditch
and he never reached the doctor ,
so there couldn 't have been any
experimental blood transfusion that saved her life .
Misery was buried in the ground at the end , Paul .
So , you 'll have to start there .
( subdued music )
Is it fair ?
Should I continue ?
You better .
Oh , Paul .
When Ian realized that the reason they 'd buried Misery alive
was because the bee sting had put her
in that temporary coma .
And when Gravedigger Wilkes remembered how 30 years earlier
the same thing had happened to Lady Evelyn-Hyde .
And then old Dr. Cleary deduced that Misery
must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde 's long-lost daughter
because of the rarity of deadly bee stings ,
my heart just leapt !
( laughs )
I 've known from the very first book
that Misery had to be born of nobility and I was right .
Yeah , yeah .
Oh , Paul .
Can I read each chapter when you finish ?
I can fill in the Ns .
Will she be her old self now that Ian has dug her out ,
or will she have amnesia ?
Have to wait .
Will she still love him with that special , perfect love ?
You 'll have to wait .
Not even a hint ?
Mm-mm .
( yells )
Misery 's alive , Misery 's alive !
Oh , it 's so romantic !
This whole house is gonna be filled with romance !
I 'm gonna put on my Liberace records !
You do like Liberace , don 't you ?
Whenever he played Radio City ,
who do you think was right there in the front row ?
I 'm gonna play my records all day long , to inspire you .
He 's my all-time favorite .
Annie .
Would you have dinner with me tonight
to celebrate Misery 's Return ?
I couldn 't have done it without you .
Oh , Paul .
It would be an honor .
No , he 's not here .
I don 't know where he is .
He never tells me anything anymore .
He 's probably out havin ' an affair somewhere .
Wait a minute .
He 's comin ' in now .
It 's Jim Taylor .
He wants to know who you 're havin ' an affair with .
Hello , Jim .
What 's doin ' ?
Jim , we 've been through this before .
If you 're gonna have benches out in front of your store ,
people are gonna want to sit on ' em .
Well , I don 't like him either ,
but I 'm not gonna come over there and tell him to move .
Give my best to Denise .
Bye .
Well , whoever she is , she sure likes to read a lot .
Virginia , I 'm flattered that you think
I 've got that much energy .
I figured that if I can 't find Paul Sheldon ,
at least I can find out what he wrote about .
What do you expect to find ?
A story about a guy who drove his car
off a cliff in a snowstorm ?
You see , it 's just that kind of sarcasm
that 's given our marriage real spice .
♫ I 'll be seeing you
♫ In all the old familiar places
I hope you like it .
It looks wonderful .
So do you .
( laughs )
♫ All day through
♫ In that small cafe
♫ The park across the way
♫ The children 's carousel
I 've never had meatloaf this good .
What do you do to it ?
My secret is I only use fresh tomatoes , never canned .
And to give it that little extra zip ,
I mix in some Spam with the ground beef .
Ah .
Can 't get this in a restaurant in New York .
( Annie laughs )
♫ That this heart of mine embraces
Let 's have a toast .
A toast ?
Yes .
To Misery .
Let me pour you some wine .
♫ In that small cafe
[ Annie ] Whoa .
Hmm ?
No . ( laughs )
♫ The children 's carousel
To Misery .
( glasses clink )
Wait .
Let 's do this right .
Do you have any candles ?
Oh , um , I don 't know .
I think so .
I 'll go look .
Did you study decorating or do you just have a flair ?
[ Annie ] Oh , you !
I just picked things up over the years .
Well , it certainly says you .
[ Annie ] You really think so ?
Oh , absolutely .
Listen , if you can 't find any , it 's okay .
I just thought it 'd be nice .
Are you kidding ?
If anyone had ever told me that one day
I 'd be having a candlelit dinner
with Paul Sheldon in my own house ,
I would 've checked both legs
to see which one was bein ' pulled .
( both laugh )
Will this do ?
It 's perfect .
To Misery and to Annie Wilkes , who brought her back to life .
Oh , Paul .
I get goosebumps every time I think about it .
Oh , oh , oh , oh .
Oh , my God , what have I done ?
Oh , I 'm so sorry , Paul .
I ruined your beautiful toast .
Will you ever forgive me ?
Here , let me pour another one .
Can we pretend this never happened ?
To Misery .
( glasses clink )
( " Tchaikovsky 's Piano Concerto No. 1 " by Liberace )
( typewriter clacking )
Paul , this is positively the best Misery
you 've ever written .
( typewriter clacking )
( bell dings )
( thunder rumbling )
Here 's your pills .
Annie ?
Annie , what is it ?
The rain .
Sometimes it gives me the blues .
When you first came here ,
I only loved the writer part of Paul Sheldon .
But , now I know I love the rest of him , too .
I know you don 't love me .
Don 't say you do .
You 're a beautiful , brilliant , famous man of the world
and I 'm not a movie-star type .
You 'll never know the fear of losing someone like you ,
if you 're someone like me .
Why would you lose me ?
The book 's almost finished .
Your legs are getting better .
Soon , you 'll be wanting to leave .
Why would I leave ?
I like it here .
That 's very kind of you ,
but I 'll bet it 's not altogether true .
( thunder rumbles )
I have this gun .
( gun clicks )
Sometimes I think about using it .
I better go now .
I might put bullets in it .
( door closes )
( thunder rumbles )
( car engine starts )
( tense music )
There is a justice higher than that of man .
I will be judged by Him .
What ?
They 're haulin ' Misery into court .
That 's nice .
There is a justice higher than that of man .
I will be judged by Him .
( suspenseful music )
( thunder rumbles )
( thunder rumbling )
( car approaching )
( car door opens and closes )
( footsteps tapping )
( door opens and closes )
( door closes )
[ Man On TV ] Welcome to Love Connection .
( chattering on TV )
See you in the morning .
( thunder clapping ) ( ominous music )
( grunts )
( door closes )
[ Man On TV ] I 'm supposed to lead you
to the finale of my show right now ,
but I 'm having such a wonderful time ...
[ Annie ] Paul .
[ Man On TV ] So , if you 'd like me stay
and play some more for you , I 'd love to .
Hmm ?
I know you 've been out .
What ?
You 've been out of your room .
No , I haven 't .
Paul , my little ceramic penguin in the study
always faces due south .
( " Moonlight Sonata " by Liberace )
I don 't know what you 're talking about .
Ceramic penguin ?
Is this what you 're looking for ?
I know you 've been out twice , Paul .
At first I couldn 't figure out how you did it ,
but last night I found your key .
I know I left my scrapbook out .
I can imagine what you might be thinking of me .
But you see , Paul , it 's all okay .
Last night it came so clear .
I realize you just need more time .
Eventually , you 'll come to accept the idea of being here .
Paul , do you know about the early days
at the Kimberley diamond mines ?
Do you know what they did to the native workers
who stole diamonds ?
Don 't worry .
They didn 't kill them .
That would be like junking a Mercedes
just because it had a broken spring .
No , if they caught them they had to make sure
they could go on working ,
but they also had to make sure they could never run away .
The operation was called hobbling .
Annie , whatever you 're thinking about doing ,
please don 't do it .
Annie , for God 's ...
Shh , darling .
Trust me .
God 's sake !
It 's for the best .
[ Paul ] Annie , please !
( screaming )
Almost done .
Just one more .
( screaming )
God , I love you .
( tires squealing )
( horn honking )
You cockadoodie !
[ Man ] Sit on this !
[ Annie ] You poop !
( uptempo music )
Just leave it , all right ?
Oh , I like that tone .
How many times do I have to tell you ?
I have a system here .
Where the hell is that thing ?
[ Virginia ] What thing ?
The thing .
Here it is , right where it 's supposed to be .
What is it ?
I 'm not sure .
Maybe nothin ' .
Well , I 'm glad you found it .
[ Buster ] There 's that spice again .
( subdued music )
( car door opens and closes )
Come on , Misie .
Come on .
Hi , pumpkin .
Such a kidder .
Come on , Misery .
( snorting )
Come on , Misie .
Hey , Pete .
Buster .
Answer me a couple things .
[ Pete ] If I can .
Do you have any new Paul Sheldon books ?
Well , we had a batch .
Sold ' em all out in three days .
You wouldn 't happen to know if Ms. Wilkes
bought one of them , would you ?
Are you kiddin ' ?
Every time that fella writes a new book ,
she has me set aside the first copy .
Has she been buyin ' anything odd lately ?
Ms. Wilkes ?
Same old stuff .
Lest you call paper odd .
Newspaper ?
No .
Typin ' kind .
Oh , that kind .
Nothin ' odd about that .
Ms. Wilkes done somethin ' ?
[ Buster ] Not a thing .
( uptempo music )
( car approaching )
( footsteps approaching )
( yells )
( grunting )
I don 't think I 'll ever understand you .
I cook your meals ,
I tend to you practically 24 hours a day ,
and you continue to fight me .
When are we going to develop a sense of trust ?
( suspenseful music )
Oh , my .
I 'm sorry , I didn 't mean to startle you ,
but you didn 't give me a chance to knock .
I guess you can tell from my reaction
I 'm not all that used to visitors out here .
What can I do for you ?
Well , I was wonderin ' .
Do you happen to know anything about Paul Sheldon ?
What do you want to know ?
Well , anything you could tell me might help .
Well , he was born in Worcester , Massachusetts
45 years ago , the only child of Franklin and Helene Sheldon ,
mediocre student , majored in History ...
Well , that isn 't exactly the kind of information I 'm after .
You see , he 's been missin ' for quite some time now ...
I know .
It 's so upsetting .
I 'm his number one fan .
I 've got all his books .
Every sentence he ever put down .
I 'm so proud of my Paul Sheldon collection .
Well , here I am prattling on ,
and my manners have just flown away .
I haven 't invited you in .
Please .
Thank you .
Of course , you must know all about that horrible accident .
Mind if I take a look around ?
Of course not .
That accident almost killed me , too .
I prayed when I heard the news .
I got down on my knees and I begged for it not to be true .
You 're gonna laugh at what I 'm about to say ,
but go ahead , I don 't care .
When I was praying , God told me to get ready .
[ Buster ] Get ready for what ?
To be his replacement .
He gave so much pleasure to so many people ,
and there 's a shortage of pleasure on the planet these days ,
in case you hadn 't noticed .
God told me , since I was his number one fan ,
that I should make up new stories as if I was Paul Sheldon .
So , I went to town and I bought a typewriter
and paper to type on .
The same kind Paul Sheldon used .
And I turned the guest bedroom into a writing studio .
Would you like to see it ?
Sure .
It 's right this way .
( footsteps thumping )
I know how he wrote .
The kinds of words he used , the wonderful stories he told .
I 've spent the last four weeks
trying to write like Paul Sheldon , but I can 't do it right .
I try , and I try , and I know all the words ,
but it 's just not the same .
Well , maybe it takes a while to get the hang of it .
I could give you a couple of hundred pages of mine
and you could tell me what you think .
I 'm not much of a critic .
Well , I just thought .
Oh , look at me .
You 'd think I 'd never had a guest before .
Would you like a nice hot cup of cocoa ?
No , really .
I don 't care .
It 's no trouble .
There 's some already made .
Must get lonely , livin ' out here all by yourself .
Well , I always say , if you can 't enjoy your own company ,
you 're not fit company for anyone else .
[ Buster ] Well , you 've got a point there .
( chuckles )
( both laugh )
( footsteps thumping )
( tense music )
( wood creaks )
Here you are .
Well , thanks , Ms. Wilkes ,
but I don 't want to take up any more of your time .
I 'd best be goin ' .
But , you didn 't even taste your cocoa .
I 'm sure it 's wonderful ,
but I really should be gettin ' back .
Well , if you wouldn 't mind ,
perhaps I could pay you another visit sometime .
I 'd be delighted , now that you know the way .
( clattering )
Ms. Wilkes ?
Ms. Wilkes , are you all right ?
Here !
I 'm down here !
Down here !
Mr. Sheldon ?
( gun fires )
Don 't feel bad , Paul .
It was bound to happen sooner or later .
It 's a sign .
You see , I 've known for some time
why I was chosen to save you .
You and I were meant to be together forever .
But , now our time in this world must end .
But , don 't worry , Paul .
I 've prepared for what must be done .
I put two bullets in my gun , one for you and one for me .
Oh , darling .
It 'll be so beautiful .
Now , don 't be afraid .
I love you .
I love you , too .
And you 're right .
We are meant to be together .
And I know we must die .
But , it must be so that Misery can live .
We have the power to give Misery eternal life .
We must finish the book .
But , the time is now .
Soon , others will come .
It 's almost finished .
By dawn , we 'll be able to give Misery
back to the world .
I 'll fix you something to eat .
( typewriter clacking )
Oh , Paul .
I 'm dying .
Does she wind up with Ian or Windthorne ?
You 'll know very soon .
I 've just started the last chapter .
You know , when I finish ,
I 'd like everything to be perfect .
I 'll need three things .
What things ?
You mean you don 't know ?
( laughs )
I was foolin ' , silly .
You need a cigarette because you used to smoke ,
but you quit , except when you finish a book ,
and you have just one .
And the match is to light it .
And you need one glass of champagne , Dom Perignon .
Dom Perignon it is .
( typewriter clacking )
Annie ?
Yes , Paul ?
I 'm almost done .
Oh , Paul .
This is so romantic .
Ian and Windthorne dueling for the right to Misery 's hand .
Does Ian win ?
Oh , don 't tell me .
It 's Windthorne , right ?
You 'll know everything in a minute .
Get the champagne .
Oh , oh .
( typewriter clacking )
Did I do good ?
You did perfect .
Except for one thing .
This time we 'll need two glasses .
Oh , Paul .
( suspenseful music )
Remember how , for all those years ,
nobody knew who Misery 's real father was ?
Or if they 'd ever be reunited ?
It 's all right here .
Does she finally marry Ian , or will it be Windthorne ?
Paul , you can 't !
( glass shatters )
Why not ?
I learned it from you .
No , no , no !
Not Misery !
Not my Misery !
No !
( gasping )
( grunting )
I 'm gonna kill you , you lying cocksucker !
( glass breaks )
( screams )
( grunting )
( gun fires )
( yells )
( grunting )
Here .
Here , you want it ?
You want it ?
Eat it !
Eat it till you choke , you sick , twisted fuck !
( grunts )
( bell dings )
( breathing heavily )
( yells )
( screaming )
( grunting )
( metal clangs )
( breathing heavily )
Good choice .
It really was .
This is it .
The very first copy .
The word I 'm getting is the Times review
is gonna be a love letter .
That 'll be a first .
And my contacts at Time and Newsweek
tell me they 're both raves .
And don 't laugh , but for the first time
I think you 've got a shot at some prizes .
Great .
I thought you 'd be thrilled .
You 're being taken seriously .
I 'm delighted the critics are liking it
and I hope the people like it , too .
But , I wrote it for me .
Now , don 't think I 'm completely nuts ,
but in some way ,
Annie Wilkes , that whole experience ,
helped me .
Paul , since you brought her up , I have to ask you this
or I 'll be drummed out of the agents ' union .
How would you feel about a non-fiction book
about what went on in that house ?
Gee , Marcia .
If I didn 't know you better ,
I 'd think you were suggesting I dredge up
the worst horror of my life just so we can make a few bucks .
[ Marcia ] I thought you were over it .
I don 't know if anyone could ever totally
get over something like that .
It 's weird .
Even though I know she 's dead ,
I still think about her once in a while .
Excuse me .
I don 't mean to bother you , but are you Paul Sheldon ?
Yes .
I just want to tell you I 'm your number one fan .
That 's very sweet of you .
♫ I 'll be seeing you
♫ In all the old familiar places
♫ That this heart of mine embraces
♫ All day through
♫ In that small cafe
♫ The park across the way
♫ The children 's carousel
♫ The chestnut trees
♫ The wishing well
♫ I 'll be seeing you
♫ In every lovely summer 's day
♫ In everything that 's light and gay
♫ I 'll always think of you that way
♫ I 'll find you in the morning sun
♫ And when the night is new
♫ I 'll be looking at the moon
♫ But , I 'll be seeing you
♫ I 'll be seeing you
♫ In every lovely summer 's day
♫ In everything that 's light and gay
♫ I 'll always think of you that way
♫ I 'll find you in the morning sun
♫ And when the night is new
♫ I 'll be looking at the moon
♫ But , I 'll be seeing you